Jonathan Waldman

Tel Aviv-Yafo, Tel Aviv, Israel



jonathanywaldman@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jonathanwaldman

Summary

I am an experienced Security Engineer who uses a background in the natural sciences to assist me in my role as a security professional. My expertise include the administrative duties of the profession to the highly technical and sophisticated nature of penetration testing and hacking. Some current goals of mine include reverse engineering and exploit development.

Experience



Application Security Architect

Mar 2021 - Present (5 months +)

Pentester

Cobalt

May 2019 - Present (2 years 3 months +)

Senior Security Engineer

Watermark

Aug 2018 - Mar 2021 (2 years 8 months)

- Conducted extensive internal and external network and application penetration tests utilizing industry standard exploitation tools and techniques
- Guided developers and DevOps engineers on remediation strategies for critical vulnerabilities
- · Launched a security training program for all Watermark employees that targeted specific job functions
- Introduced company wide initiatives on GDPR, PCI, and FERPA compliance
- Completed the SOC2 audit process and obtained SOC2 certification
- Interacted with clients' security teams to ensure risks are clearly addressed and to alleviate any security concerns
- Instituted industry best-practice auditing of software, hardware, user accounts, etc.

Software Developer and Network Security Engineer

GETIDA

Oct 2016 - Aug 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Network and Security Engineer

- · Enforced security protocols necessary to prevent the exploitation (via MITM, XSS, SQL injection, brute force, session hijacking, and more) of proprietary software
- Conducted in-depth code reviews and security tests of the web app, back-end, and critical infrastructure
- Managed the migration of servers, data stores, and client systems to the cloud
- Oversaw infrastructure security by deploying IDS and firewalls thereby saving more than \$50,000/yr

- · Administered secure and redundant MySQL databases responsible for storing confidential and sensitive customer information along with tens of thousands of entries per customer
- Deployed and configured a native email server tailored for custom management

Java and JavaScript Developer

- Designed and implemented a unique 4-way communication protocol in Java that allows efficient and secure communication in the client-server architecture
- · Coordinated the integration of the back-end server and data store with the front-end using NodeJS npm packages to provide secure communication
- · Analyzed and improved the algorithms responsible for calculating legitimate and probabilistically successful claims to be submitted to FBA centers
- Built a billing and invoicing system that integrates third-party payment APIs with the system that manages reimbursed items from FBA centers



Chemical Researcher

Yeshiva University

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016 (1 year 3 months)

- Thesis Title: Metal catalyzed Cross-Coupling of 1,8-Diaminonaphthalenes and Aryl Halides
- Devised a new general methodology for synthesis of 1,8-Bis(arylamino)naphthalene molecules
- Utilized NMR, GC-MS and other standard spectroscopic techniques
- · Advisor: Dr. James Camara



Resident Advisor

Yeshiva University

May 2013 - Jun 2016 (3 years 2 months)

- · Advised students on all aspects of university life and cared for their individual needs
- Planned fun and diverse floor parties
- · Acted decisively in emergency situations



Lifeguard and Recreational Staff

Camp Hasc

Jun 2012 - Aug 2012 (3 months)

Lifeguard

- Protected children with special needs while they engaged in therapy in the pool
- · Improved the body-coordination of children with special needs by stimulating their nerves
- Supervised the function of the pool

Recreational Staff

- Organized programming for children with a ride range of special needs
- · Provided an entertaining and engaging atmosphere for the kids



Mathematics Tutor

Self Employed

Sep 2010 - Jun 2011 (10 months)

- Mentored students preparing for the New York State Regents Exams
- Provided students with a unique perspective on how to approach mathematical problems

Student Intern

Florida Cardiology Group

Jul 2010 - Aug 2010 (2 months)

- Witnessed surgeries in the operating room of Bethesda Memorial Hospital, Boynton Beach, Florida
- · Assisted Dr. Borzak, MD in the examination room

Education



Bachelor's Degree, Chemistry 2011 - 2015 Studied chemistry and Hebrew

Yeshivat Sha'alvim

2011 - 2012

Yeshiva Far Rockaway

Licenses & Certifications

- Lifeguarding/First Aid/CPR/AED American Red Cross
- Ethical Hacking From Beginner to Advanced Technique Udemy
- (ISC) Associate of (ISC)2 CISSP (ISC)2
- OSCP PWK Offensive Security
- OSWE AWAE Offensive Security

Skills

Tutoring • Swimming Instructor • Time Management • Public Health • Event Planning • Leadership • Healthcare Management • Treatment • Medical Education • Microsoft Excel

Honors & Awards

Valedictorian of graduating class - Yeshiva Far Rockaway
Jun 2011

Friendship Circle Achievement Award

Jun 2011

- Young Israel of West Hempstead Distinguished Service Award
 Jun 2011
- Daniel Ladell Memorial Award for Excellence in Chemistry Yeshiva University
 May 2016
- Dr. Samuel Soloveichik Prize for Excellence in the Study of Natural Sciences Yeshiva University

 May 2016